Hey there, so I've
been thinking a lot
about AI
and its impact on
our world.
We're always bombarded
with stories
of how it's gonna
revolutionize
industries
and replace human
workers.
But as a computer
science student,
I've had the chance
to dig deeper
and my perspective
has really evolved.
When cars were
first invented,
people thought
flying cars would
be just around the
corner,
but we're still
stuck in traffic
today.
Similarly, when
smartphones came
out,
everyone was like,
this is going to
change everything.
But reality sets in
much sooner than we
expect.
When a new
technology comes
along,
we get caught up in
the excitement and
promise
of what it can do,
but often it doesn't
live up to our
expectations.
That's why I truly
believe AI is not
going
to replace us as
programmers.
Instead, it's going
to augment our
skills and
abilities
in ways we can't
even imagine yet.
The problem is that
many students
treat computer
science like a
chore,
seeing it just as
something they need
to pass their
classes or get a
job.
But coding should
be about the
journey itself,
problem solving,
creativity,
sense of
accomplishment when
we figure something
out.
I didn't start with
some grand vision
of creating
something massive
and impactful.
I began my building
small projects
that I actually
cared about.
Whether it was
automating tasks on
my computer
or creating a
simple game,
I enjoyed the
process of learning
and experimenting.
That's what I want
to leave you with
today.
Find the excitement
in coding again.
We need to build
projects that
matter to us.
Learn from our
failures and push
ourselves
to be better every
day.
Don't just learn
how to code.
Learn how to
problem solve.
When we do that, we'll
realize that coding
isn't just
about what we can
build or achieve.
It's about who we
are as people.
And when you're
wondering whether
AI is going
to replace us, ask
yourself,
when will AI make
my life easier or
more interesting?
The grind may not
always feel
exciting,
but it's worth it
in the end.
So keep pushing
yourself to be
better,
keep learning, and
never lose sight
of why you started
coding in the first
place
for the love of it.
And don't forget to
like, subscribe,
and comment below
with your thoughts.